         Dr. Seuss' The Lorax


         Screenplay by 
        Cinco Paul & Ken Daurio

         Based on the Book by           Dr. Seuss
          Dr. Seuss

      INT: THEATER - DAY

      The Lorax steps onto the stage in front of a large curtain      and addresses the camera.
      and addresses the camera.

               LORAX
          Hello, everybody. Thanks for 
          coming.

      The Lorax CLEARS his throat and reads from a card he holds.

               LORAX (CONT'D)
          I am the Lorax. I speak for the 
          trees.
          And I'd like to say a few words, if 
          you please,
          Regarding the story that you're 
          'bout to see--
          It actually happened--just take it 
          from me.
          But there's more to this story than 
          what's on the page,
          So please pay attention while I set 
          the stage.

      The Lorax tosses the card at the audience and walks off as      the curtain opens, revealing Thneedville.
      the curtain opens, revealing Thneedville.


      EXT. THNEEDVILLE - DAY

      TWO MAINTENANCE WORKERS work on a large "Welcome to 
      Thneedville" sign. The slogan below it reads, "Fantastic! Made of plastic! 100% Inorganic." The camera pushes past them and flies through the town, down to a suburban street.

               LORAX (V.0.)
          We open in Thneedville, a city,
          they say,
          That was plastic and fake, and they
          liked it that way.
          A Town Without Nature. Not one
          living tree.
          So what happened to them?
          Cue the music! 
          Let's see...


      EXT. THNEEDVILLE - PRESENT - MORNING 

      SONG: "THNEEDVILLE"

      The MUSIC starts up on a LONG SHOT down the street of 
      Thneedville suburbs.

 Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 2.


All of the houses look basically the same. Electric trees 
line the streets instead of street lamps.

An O'Hare Air delivery truck drives down the street.

FLOOSH! An INFLATABLE PLASTIC BUSH inflates. FLOOSH! 
Another. FLOOSH! Another. Then--

POP! a bed of PLASTIC FLOWERS pops up in time with the music 
complete with PLASTIC BUZZING BEES attached to wires.

                   PLASTIC BEES 
             (mechanical voice) 
         Buzz! Buzz! Buzz!

The DELIVERY MAN gets out of the truck and grabs an air 
bottle from it. He replaces an empty, used air bottle with a 
new one like a milkman.


TITLE CARD: DR. SEUSS' THE LORAX 


EXT: TED'S HOUSE - PRESENT - SAME

Nearby, TED, an 11-year-old boy and our hero, hops out of his 
second floor bedroom window, down a series of stairs, and 
flips over the railing into the air and lands on his SCOOTER.

He snaps on his goggles, revs his engine, and takes off down 
the street. PULL BACK TO A WIDE SHOT of the entire 
neighborhood.

All of the front doors of the houses open simultaneously and 
the PEOPLE OF THNEEDVILLE exit their houses singing happily.

                   EVERYONE
         In Thneedville it's a brand new 
         dawn!

PEOPLE drive by in their personalized vanity cars, including 
a BUSINESSMAN in his large STEAMROLLER SUV.

                   EVERYONE (CONT'D)
         With brand new cars
         And houses
         And lawns!

We pull back to see the rest of the neighborhood joining the 
traffic. Ted follows behind them on his scooter.

                   EVERYONE (CONT'D)
         Here in got-all-that-we-need-ville!

 Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 3.


A MAN uses a bike pump to inflate his flaccid plastic bush. 
He's not paying attention and pumps the bush until it POPS, 
knocking him over.


EXT: ROAD INTO TOWN - PRESENT - SAME

The people of Thneedville sing as they commute to work past 
rows of FAKE TREES.
                   EVERYONE
         In Thneedville we manufacture our 
         trees
A little Girl, MARIE, uses a tire swing hanging from a metal 
tree.
                   EVERYONE (CONT'D) 
         Each one is made in factories.

MAINTENANCE MEN opens up a PANEL in the electric tree 
revealing it's filled with BATTERIES.
                   MAINTENANCE MAN 
         And uses 96 batteries!

The lights on the tree go out as the batteries fall out. One 
of the Maintenance Men quickly tries to pick them up.
Ted rides by on his scooter.

The Singing Delivery Man walks up to an apartment, carrying a 
large O'HARE AIR BOTTLE.
                   EVERYONE
         In Thneedville the air's not so 
         clean
The Singing Delivery Man walks into a WOMAN'S APARTMENT. 


INT: APARTMENT - PRESENT - SAME

A WOMAN opens the door and lets the Singing Delivery Man in. 
He replaces the large bottle of O'Hare Air hooked to her 
Fresh Air System.

                   WOMAN
         So we buy it fresh!
The Singing Delivery Man PLOPS the bottle into the machine in 
time with the beat. She hands him money for the delivery.

 Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 4.


                   SINGING DELIVERY MAN 
         It comes out this machine!

She takes a whiff of the fresh air. He takes a whiff of the 
money.

                   WOMAN & SINGING DELIVERY MAN
         Aaaaah!

                   EVERYONE
         In satisfaction's guaranteed-ville!


EXT: DOWNTOWN - PRESENT - SAME

Downtown a group of BUSINESSPEOPLE sing and dance as they 
head for work. The Maintenance Workers sweep garbage towards 
an open manhole.

                   EVERYONE 
         In Thneedville

The Singing Delivery Man jumps in front of the Maintenance 
Works and starts dancing.

                   SINGING DELIVERY MAN 
         We don't want to kn0000w!

He does a spin and accidentally disappears down a MANHOLE.

                   EVERYONE
         Where the smog and trash and 
         chemicals go

A LITTLE BOY swims through the Thneedville River (which is 
unnaturally blue) wearing a big smile. His parents happily 
help him out of the river and give him a big hug.

                   LITTLE BOY
         I just went swimming, and now I 
         glow!

He glows and smiles even more. Ted zips by him on the 
scooter.


EXT: MIDDLE OF TOWN - PRESENT - SAME

We see a CHUBBY SURFER surfing on the fake ocean. A 
SNOWBOARDING TEEN zips down the snowy mountain next to him.

                   EVERYONE
         In Thneedville we have fun year- 
         round!

 Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 5.


The Snowboarding Teen turns and sends a CLUMP OF SLUSH flying 
and it goes down the back of a GUY'S SWIMSUIT.

                   EVERYONE (CONT'D)
         We surf and snowboard right in 
         town!

A group of SUNBATHERS sing like a church choir, holding their 
sun reflectors like choir folders.

                   SUNBATHING CHOIR
         We thank the Lord for all we've 
         got!

The Singing Delivery Man sings a beautiful solo as we reveal 
that the choir is singing at the grand opening of a new 
PARKING LOT (called Thneedville Parking).

                   SUNBATHING MAN
         Including this brand new parking 
         lot!

As the choir sings with religious fervor about the parking 
lot, people step our of their parked vehicles, get on the 
roofs of their cars, and JOYOUSLY sing along.

                   EVERYONE
         Parking lot! 
         Parking lot!

Nearby a WOMAN and her SON fly kites propelled by large fans.

                   WOMAN WITH KITE
         It's him!

Everyone looks up and sees the O'HARE AIR BLIMP, which spews 
out smog from its exhaust. Projected on it's massive LCD 
screen is ALOYSIUS O'HARE, the financial king of Thneedville, 
owner of the O'Hare Air Co. Pudgy and clownish and tacky and 
loved by everyone. He leans out from the window and waves to 
the people down below.

                   EVERYONE
         Ooh look! It's Aloysius O'Hare 
         (Aloysius O'Hare)
         The man who found a way to sell air


INT: BLIMP - PRESENT - SAME

O'HARE turns around in his office chair and walks out from 
behind his desk.

 Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 6.


EXT: THNEEDVILLE - PRESENT - SAME

O'Hare stands on Mooney's hands outside the door.

                   O'HARE
         And became a zillionaire!

He dives off and falls down toward the ground. His parachute 
opens revealing an ad for O'Hare Air.

                   EVERYONE 
         Hip-hooray, hip-hooray!

As they celebrate we catch up with Ted, who is excitedly 
buying a REMOTE CONTROL AIRPLANE from a VENDOR at his kiosk. 
He gives the vendor his money and takes the new airplane, 
ecstatic.

                   EVERYONE (CONT'D) 
         Hip-hip-hooray!

We're in the center of town. Here comes the elaborately 
choreographed big finish, reminiscent of "Consider Yourself" 
from Oliver.

The huge mob engulfs Ted at the toy kiosk. People dance with 
their shopping bags, tossing them to each other. 
Businesspeople dance with their briefcases.

                   EVERYONE (CONT'D) 
         In Thneedville
         We love living this way!

Suddenly the Singing Delivery Man reappears in frame, pushes 
the BAND LEADER aside, grabs his baton, and leads the 
MARCHING BAND down the street.

                   SINGING DELIVERY MAN 
         It's like living in paradise!

                   EVERYONE
         It's perfect!
         And that's how it will stay!

                   SINGING DELIVERY MAN
         Oh yeah!

Fireworks go off above the town.

O'Hare walks up the steps of his oversized limo waving to the 
people like a politician before he gets in.

The Singing Delivery Man dances on top of O'Hare's limo while 
spinning cheer-leading batons.

 Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 7.


                   EVERYONE
         Here in love the life we lead-ville 
         Destined to succeed-ville
         We are all agreed-ville
         We're happy here in

CLOSE-UPS on various MOUTHS making the "thhh" sound.

                   EVERYONE (CONT'D)
         Thhhh--

Back to the wide shot showing the entire center of town.

                   EVERYONE (CONT'D) 
         --needville!

As soon as the song's over, everyone immediately goes back to 
what they were doing. Mooney and McGurk help the frozen 
Singing Delivery Man off the roof of the limo.

And out of the crowd zips Ted on his scooter, carrying the 
bag with the airplane in it.


EXT: THNEEDVILLE - PRESENT - SAME

Ted rides his scooter through town with the confidence of 
someone who knows the place like the back of his hand.


EXT: AUDREY'S HOUSE - PRESENT - CONTINUOUS

He ends up suburbia. Stops in front of a house. Gets off of 
his scooter. Reaches into the bag and pulls out the REMOTE- 
CONTROLLED AIRPLANE. Ted smiles as he admires it.

Ted places it on the ground. Operates the remote control, 
and it TAKES OFF. Ted then flies the plane in a series of 
loop-dee-loops and then straight into someone's backyard. 
But instead of being upset, he smiles.

                   TED
         Yes.

He runs up to the front door of the house. RINGS the 
doorbell. Multiple times. As the door opens, Ted goes into 
a slow-mo fantasy, revealing--

AUDREY. A teenage girl, beautiful and cool, and much too old 
for Ted. Although he doesn't see it that way. He looks up 
at her worshipfully, suddenly awkward in her presence.

                   AUDREY 
         Oh, hi, Ted.

 Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 8.


Ted breaks out of the fantasy.

                   TED
             (trying to play it cool) 
         Oh, hey, Audrey. Hi.

                   AUDREY
         Did your ball land in my backyard 
         again?

                   TED
         What?! No. Model airplane. This 
         time.

Audrey smiles. Then leans in to Ted, conspiratorially.

                   AUDREY
         Hey--do you wanna see something 
         cool?

Ted stares back at Audrey. Are you kidding me?

                   AUDREY (CONT'D)
         Come on!

Audrey turns to go into the house. Ted follows her, spraying 
breath freshener into his mouth as he enters.


EXT: AUDREY'S BACKYARD - PRESENT - LATER

Audrey takes her hands away from Ted's eyes and he looks up 
to see a MASSIVE MURAL in progress on the wall depicting a 
lush valley filled with TRUFFULA TREES. Ted stares up at the 
painting in awe.

                   TED
         Whoa. Did you p-- Did you paint 
         this?

                   AUDREY
         Do you like it?

                   TED
         What?! Are you kidding? This is 
         amazing.
             (points to trees)
         What are those?

                   AUDREY 
             (smiles)
         Those are trees. Real ones.
         They used to grow all around here.
                   (MORE)

 Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 9.

                   AUDREY (CONT'D)
         And people said that the touch of 
         their tufts was softer than
         anything, even silk. And they 
         smelled like butterfly milk.

                   TED
         Wow. What does that even mean?

                   AUDREY
         I know, right?

Audrey grabs Ted's arms and swings him over her head, so they 
both fall to the ground.

                   TED
         Whaaaa!
             (pained) 
         Oh yeah.

                   AUDREY
         What I want more than anything in 
         the whole world is to see a real 
         living tree, growing in my
         backyard.

                   TED
             (thinking)
         So...if, say-- I'm just thinking 
         out loud here... if a guy somehow 
         got you one...

                   AUDREY
         Well, I'd probably marry him on the 
         spot.
             (makes a face)
         I bet that sounds crazy. Does that 
         sound crazy?

Ted looks up adoringly at Audrey.

                   TED
         No. Not crazy!
             (clears his throat) 
         Not crazy at all.

Ted smiles. A boy with a plan. 


INT: DINING ROOM - PRESENT - NIGHT

Ted sits at the dinner table with his MOM and GRAMMY NORMA. 
He absentmindedly pokes at a PIECE OF JELLO shaped like 
BROCCOLI.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 10.


                   TED'S MOM
         Ted, honey, don't play with your 
         food. You either, Mom.

Grammy Norma dribbles a JELLO BROCCOLI like a basketball. 
She tosses it up and pops it in her mouth.

                   TED
         So...Mom. Do you happen to know if 
         there's like anyplace where I could 
         get a real tree?

Grammy Norma reacts to this.

                   TED'S MOM
         Ted, we already have a tree. It's 
         the latest model.

                   TED
         Yeah, but I mean like a real one,
         that-- that grows out of the ground 
         or whatever. You know, like a real 
         tree.

                   TED'S MOM
             (makes face)
         Really? You'd rather have some
         dirty, messy lump of wood that just 
         sticks out of the ground and it 
         does what? I don't even know what 
         it does. What's it's purpose?
         Look what we've got. It's the Oak- 
         a-matic--the only tree with its own 
         remote!

She points a REMOTE at the tree outside.

                   TED'S MOM (CONT'D) 
         Summer, autumn, winter--

The tree changes with each click to match the season.

                   TED'S MOM (CONT'D) 
         --and disco!

The tree now lights up in neon colors like a disco floor. 
And plays a Muzak version of "The Hustle." Ted's Mom 
shimmies and sings along.

                   TED'S MOM (CONT'D)
         Doot doot doot doo-doot doo-doot 
         doot doot! Come on, Ted, get into 
         it, dance with the tree.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 11.


Ted sinks in his seat, mortified.

                   TED
         Mom... Oh, it hurts Mom. Please 
         stop.

Ted's Mom clicks the remote and the music stops.

                   TED (CONT'D)
         S00000, anyway, let's just say I 
         need a tree. Where would I go? 
         What do I do?

                   GRAMMY NORMA
         Then you know what? You'd need to 
         find the Once-ler.

Ted turns to Grammy Norma, surprised.

                   TED
         The-- the what?

                   TED'S MOM
         Mom, it's not really the time for 
         one of your, you know, magical 
         fables, okay?

                   GRAMMY NORMA
         Oh, that's right. I forgot. I'm 
         old and can't even remember to put 
         my teeth in.

                   TED'S MOM
         Stand down. That's not what I 
         meant.

                   GRAMMY NORMA
         No really, I forgot my teeth.
         Would you be a dear and go get them 
         for me?

                   TED'S MOM 
             (sighs)
         Sure, mom.

She exits. As soon as she's gone Grammy Norma plops in her 
teeth and turns dramatically to Ted.

                   GRAMMY NORMA
             (conspiratorially)
         Okay, here's the deal. The Once- 
         ler is the man who knows what 
         happened to the trees. You want 
         one, you need to find him.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 12.


                   TED
             (suspicious)
         "The Once-ler"? Mmm-hm, okay. 
         Grammy is this a real thing that 
         we're talking about now?

                   GRAMMY NORMA 
         Oh, he's real, all right.

                   TED
         Well...where can I find him?

Grammy Norma appears behind Ted, scaring him. She gives him 
an intense look. CLAPS and the LIGHTS DIM.

                   GRAMMY NORMA
         "Far outside of town
         where the grass never grows
         and the wind smells slow-and-sour
         when it blows
             (makes spooky wind noises)
         ...and no birds ever sing excepting
         old crows..." 
             (suddenly) 
         CAW!!!

Ted jumps. Grammy Norma catches him.

                   TED
         Whoa! Quit doing that!

                   GRAMMY NORMA
         That's the place where the Once-ler 
         lives.

                   TED 
         Wait--outside of town?


INT: TED'S BEDROOM - PRESENT - EVENING

Ted empties an old jar filled with coins and collects THREE 
NICKELS.

                   GRAMMY NORMA (V.0.)
         People used to say if you brought 
         him fifteen cents...


INT: KITCHEN - PRESENT - EVENING

RATTLE! Ted opens up the junk drawer and retrieves a NAIL.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 13.


                   GRAMMY NORMA (V.0.) 
         ...a nail...


EXT: TED'S HOUSE - PRESENT - EVENING

Ted searches around for snails. Picks a shell up. A GREAT- 
GREAT-GREAT-GRANDFATHER SNAIL, wrinkled and with a long 
beard, pops out.

                   GRAMMY NORMA (V.0.)
         ...and the shell of a great-great- 
         great grandfather snail, he'd tell 
         you everything.

Ted smiles. He's got everything he needs. 


EXT: FAR END OF TOWN - PRESENT - NIGHT

Ted rides his scooter through to the edge of town. He looks 
up and sees a large pipe above his head with sign reading, 
"VENT OUT." He follows the pipe which leads to a door high 
up in the middle of the wall. There is no way to get to it.

Nearby, Ted spots a box on the wall with a warning sign which 
reads, "AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY." Ted looks around, opens 
the box, and pushes the red button inside, which extends a 
brick from the wall out towards him.

                   TED
         Whoa!

Other bricks extend out forming a staircase up to the door.

Ted gets back on his scooter and rides it up the stairs to 
the door where he sees a sign reading, "Outside of Town." He 
turns a lever and the door opens like a bank vault.

A RED LIGHT above the door starts blinking.

The camera continues up into the sky, where the O'Hare Air 
Blimp hovers above.


EXT: O'HARE'S BLIMP - PRESENT - NIGHT 

Establishing.


INT: O'HARE'S BLIMP - PRESENT - SAME

Aloysius O'Hare sits at his desk. Standing across from him 
are two MARKETING GUYS.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 14.


                   MARKETING GUY #1
         Mr. O'Hare, what we've got for you 
         is something that is going to take 
         O'Hare Air to the next level.

                   MARKETING GUY #2
         Now, Mr. O'Hare, I know what you're 
         thinking. One, I've gotten rich 
         selling people air that's fresher 
         than the stinky stuff outside.
         Two, here's the important one, how 
         could I possibly make even more 
         money?
             (laughs)
         We can tell you, sir, we can tell 
         you!

                   MARKETING GUY #1
         Check out this commercial. Huh?!

He clicks his remote and a COMMERCIAL appears on a screen. 


EXT: ROOFTOP - COMMERCIAL - DAY

TWO GUYS sit in chairs on a rooftop.

                   FIRST GUY
         Well, here goes another lame 
         Saturday.

                   SECOND GUY
         Dude...I don't think so. 
             (chuckles)

He smiles and pulls a six-pack of O'HARE AIR out of a cooler.

                   FIRST GUY
         Huh?

Pops one open, funky music begins playing, the sun comes out, 
and suddenly a bunch of BEAUTIFUL PEOPLE show up.

                   FIRST GUY (CONT'D)
         Hey!

                   SECOND GUY 
         Oh, yeah! Right here.

                   FIRST GUY
         Man!

                   SECOND GUY
         Oh yeah!

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 15.


TWO MEN open bottles and blow the air into their mouths.

                   FIRST GUY
         Whaaaaa?!

A hot chick opens up a bottle in her face and it makes her 
hair blow sexily. The First Guy is amazed. Instant party! 
He and his buddy click their bottles together.

                   ANNOUNCER (V.0.)
         O'Hare Purified Air. Freshness to 
         go!
             (beat)
         Please breathe responsibly.


INT: O'HARE'S OFFICE - PRESENT - SAME

The commercial over O'Hare rubs his forehead.

                   MARKETING GUY #1
         Huh?

                   MARKETING GUY #2 
         Oh my goodness.

                   MARKETING GUY #1
         Love it.

                   MARKETING GUY #2
         Yeah...

Then he speaks.

                   O'HARE
         You gotta be kidding me! You 
         really think people are stupid 
         enough to buy this?!

The Marketing Guys keep pushing each other out of the way, 
vying for O'Hare's attention.

                   MARKETING GUY #1
         Our research shows that if you put 
         something in a plastic bottle, 
         people will buy it.

                   MARKETING GUY #2 
         Exactly, and--

Marketing Guy #1 shoves Marketing Guy #2 aside and points to 
a chart showing air quality going down and sales going up.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 16.


                   MARKETING GUY #1
         And what's more, when we build a 
         new factory to make the plastic 
         bottles, the air quality's just 
         going to get worse.

                   MARKETING GUY #2
         Which will make people want our air 
         even more and drive sales... where? 
         Through the roof!

O'Hare nods his approval.

                   O'HARE
         So in other words: the more smog in 
         the sky...
             (chuckles)
         ...the more people will buy.

The Marketing Guys laugh.

                   MARKETING GUY #2
         Genius! That's why he's a genius!

                   MARKETING GUY #1 
         It even rhymes!

                   O'HARE
         I'm aware it rhymes.

Suddenly a RED LIGHT on O'Hare's desk starts flashing. He 
looks at it. The door opens and his thugs MOONEY and MCGURK 
step in. The Marketing Guys grab their charts and run off.

                   MARKETING GUY #2 (O.S.) 
         Coats! Big coats!

                   O'HARE
         What do you two knuckleheads want?! 
         I'm in the middle of a meeting!

Mooney holds out a HANDHELD DEVICE. It reads "SECURITY 
ALERT," and shows BLACK AND WHITE FOOTAGE of Ted trying to 
get out the door.

O'Hare stares at it. Frowns.

                   O'HARE (CONT'D)
         What?! Why is he leaving town? No 
         one ever leaves town!
             (beat)
         See what he's up to.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 17.


INT: WALL - PRESENT - NIGHT

Ted looks in though the door in the wall, revealing a large, 
dark room. He rides through the maze-like room on his 
scooter, passing a stream of gluppity-glup pouring out from a 
series of pipes.

                   TED
         Whoa!

A security camera watches him drive by. He continues over 
the stream on a small bridge until he reaches an exit.


EXT: OUTSIDE OF TOWN - PRESENT - CONTINUOUS

Ted comes out into the world outside of town. It's a 
desolate landscape. Filled with garbage and filthy water and 
tree stumps.

                   TED
         Huh?

He's seeing his world as it really is. And it's a nightmare.

Ted steels himself and continues on past the graveyard of 
tree stumps.

A storm brews in the smoggy sky and he looks up to see an old 
Thneed billboard. Lightning FLASHES, distracting Ted, who is 
almost beheaded by a series of old, rusted axe blades. He 
dodges and weaves through them. He looks behind him to 
reveal it's a destroyed Axe Hacker. Lightning FLASHES in the 
sky again.

                   TED (CONT'D)
         Oh, man...

Ted stops at a large ravine where a bridge is out. He looks 
around to see if there is another way to cross and spots some 
old barrels and a plank of wood. He gets an idea.


EXT: RAVINE - PRESENT - LATER

Ted revs his scooter and then takes off toward the ravine 
where he has setup the barrel and the plank of wood as a 
makeshift ramp. He intends to jump it, but as he reaches the 
end of the ramp he plummets down the side.

He SCREAMS, but picks up so much speed that he drives right 
back up the other side. He flies into the air and bounces 
back down. He breathes a SIGH OF RELIEF and continues on his 
journey up the side of a mountain pass.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax   1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform  18.


EXT: DESOLATION - PRESENT - CONTINUOUS

The city is far behind him now. Ted scooters through the 
fog, past warning signs reading, "Stay out!" and "I mean it!" 
and down the worn path where he comes to a stop in front of a 
hand-painted street sign covered in CROWS. He gets off his 
scooter and as he approaches it, the crows take off, 
revealing that it reads "The Street of the Lifted Lorax."

He keeps moving forward through the fog until he comes to a 
rickety old shack with a boarded-up window that looks like a 
strong wind might knock it over (otherwise known as The 
Lerkim). Ted stares at the spooky image, frozen. Then takes 
a deep breath and continues up the hill.

                   TED
          Whoa... All right...

He arrives in front of the Lerkim, which only looks creepier 
up close. He continues forward, not noticing that someone 
is watching him from inside the boarded up window.

Ted walks past a small ring of stones. The word "Unless" is 
carved into one of them.

Ted removes the money, nail, and snail from his pocket. The 
snail shakes his head, giving Ted a look like, "Let's get out 
of here."

Ted ignores the snail and heads up the steps leading to the 
front door. The wind whistles, and the old wood CREAKS 
beneath his feet. He gets more nervous with each step. The 
railing falls over scaring him. Then he arrives at the door 
with a sign above it reading, "THE ONCE-LER". Ted stares at 
it, then takes a deep breath and moves his shaking finger 
toward the doorbell. He presses it then--

WHIRRRRRRRR...CLANK! Immediately a crazy Seussian machine is 
activated.

                   TED (CONT'D)
          Okay...

It catapults him into the air.

                   TED (CONT'D) 
          What the--?!

A clamp catches by the seat of his pants just before he hits 
the ground and hoists him back up into the air.

                   TED (CONT'D) 
          AiIIIIIIII!

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 19.


KA-LUNK! The contraption comes to a stop, leaving Ted 
dangling in front of the Lerkim. He opens his eyes, 
surprised to be alive. Struggles to get loose.

Two YELLOW EYES and two GREEN-GLOVED ARMS appear in the 
window. Ted, still hanging upside-down, stares at them, 
horrified.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.) 
         Who are you?!

                   TED
         Aaaaaaaah!

Ted squirms and wriggles like a worm on a hook. The voice 
barks even louder.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         WHO ARE YOU?! And what are you 
         doing here?!

                   TED
             (out of breath)
         I'm Ted. I'm Ted! Oh, can't
         breathe. Are you--are you...the
         Once-ler? Oh, man.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Didn't you read the signs? No one
         is supposed to come here!

The clamp spins Ted around, lowers him to the ground and lets 
him go. Then it begins pushing him back down the path toward 
Thneedville.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.) (CONT'D) 
         Get out of here and leave me alone! 
         And don't let the boot hit you on 
         the way out.

                   TED
         The boot?

A mechanical boot kicks Ted in the butt.

                   TED (CONT'D)
         Whoa, hello! Ow...

He stops and turns back around, holding out the payment in 
his hand.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 20.


                   TED (CONT'D)
         Listen, people say that if someone 
         brings you this stuff that you'll 
         tell them about trees!

There's a pause. That word got the Once-ler's attention. 
The mechanical arm comes back and grabs Ted again bringing 
him up to the window.

                   TED (CONT'D) 
         Oh, no-no-no-no! Whoa.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Trees?

                   TED
         Yeah. Real ones, you know, that 
         grow out of the ground.

A very long pause.

                   TED (CONT'D)
         Hello?

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Sorry...it's just... Well, I 
         didn't think anyone still cared 
         about trees.

                   TED
         Well, that's me! The guy who still 
         cares. I'm here! Hey, what-- 
         Whoa!

The mechanical arm deposits Ted on the pile of rocks.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         You want to know about trees? 
         About what happened to them? Why 
         they're all gone?

Ted looks up at the window.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.) (CONT'D) 
             (whispers)
         It's because of me.

A look of shock comes over Ted's face.

                   TED 
         Wait, what?

The Once-ler lowers a long metal tube, the Whisper-Ma-Phone, 
out of his window. Ted leans in to listen.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 21.


                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         It's because of me!

The Whisper-Ma-Phone blows out dust causing Ted to COUGH.

                   ONCE-LER (0.S.) (CONT'D) 
         And my invention. The Thneed. It 
         was an amazing product that could 
         do the job of a thousand!

The Once-ler holds a Thneed out and shows it to Ted.

                   TED
         Alright...sounds ridiculous. But, 
         I mean, that's cool.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         You're darn right it was cool! 
             (sighs)
         It all started a long time ago...

                   TED
         Can we start not so long ago maybe?

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Do you want a tree?

                   TED 
         Yes. Yes...

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Then it all started a long, long 
         time ago...


EXT: ONCE-LER FAMILY HOME - PAST - DAY

Cross dissolve from Old Once-ler to a much younger Once-ler 
sitting on a COVERED WAGON which is hitched to a sad-looking 
mule named MELVIN in front of a nice house with a CAR parked 
in front. Standing there to see him off are his MOTHER, his 
moronic brothers BRETT and CHET, his monstrous GREAT-AUNT 
GRIZELDA, and his unctuous UNCLE UBB.

                   ONCE-LER (V.0.)
         I was a young man leaving home...

                   ONCE-LER
         Well, here I go, Mom. Off to 
         change the world with my Thneed! 
         I'm actually doin' it!

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 22.


                   ONCE-LER'S MOM
         Yes.
             (sweetly)
         But just remember, Oncie--if 
         somehow your invention ends up a 
         failure instead of a success...
             (abruptly switches gear) 
         Well, it wouldn't surprise me at 
         all!

The family LAUGHS at this.

                   UNCLE UBB
         Hey!

Chet punches Once-ler in the arm.

                   CHET
         Nice wheels! Burn!

Melvin kicks Chet back over toward the family. The Once-ler 
LAUGHS IT OFF.

                   ONCE-LER
         Haha. Yeah, burn! But you'll see, 
         okay--I'm gonna prove you all
         wrong! C'mon, Melvin!

More laughter from the family. The Once-ler tries to ignore 
this.


EXT: DESERT - PAST - DAY

The wagon makes its way across a country road. The Once-ler 
strums his ELECTRIC GUITAR.

                   ONCE-LER (V.0.)
         So there I was at the very bottom 
         with nothing but a wagon, a mule, 
         and a completely irrational sense 
         of optimism.

                   ONCE-LER
             (singing)
         Na na nana na na
         Oh bop-bah-da-da-do-do-do
         Thneed-Thneed-Thneed, Thneeda- 
         Thneed-Thneed-Thneed

                   ONCE-LER (V.0.) (CONT'D) 
         I was searching the globe, obsessed 
         with finding the perfect material 
         for my Thneed.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 23.


                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D) 
             (singing)
         La-la-la-la-la...


EXT: MOUNTAIN PASS - PAST - DAY

The Once-ler sleeps as MELVIN his mule continues on.

                   ONCE-LER (V.0.)
         But I'd had absolutely no success. 
         Until one day...I found paradise...

Melvin kicks the Once-ler awake.

                   ONCE-LER
             (startled)
         Oh! We're gonna be there soon! 
         I'm sure it's like-- Whoa!

PULL BACK TO REVEAL:

The TRUFFULA VALLEY. It is paradise. They look around and 
see blue skies, green grass, a flowing river, woodland 
creatures and hundreds of tall TRUFFULA TREES with their 
colorful tufts swaying in the afternoon breeze. It's 
magical.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D)
         This is the most beautiful place, 
         okay, I have ever seen.

The music swells. Then the Once-ler looks down to see THREE 
HUMMING-FISH walk up and strike a pose in front of him. They 
look up and gesture towards the beautiful valley behind them.

                   HUMMING-FISH
         Taa-daa!

They each HUM as they dive off into a nearby pond.

                   ONCE-LER
         Whoa!

The Once-ler watches as the Humming-Fish continue HUMMING 
down the hill past a fat Bar-Ba-Loot, named LOU, who stuffs 
his face with Truffula fruit. PIPSQUEAK a baby Bar-Ba-Loot 
sits next to him eating his own piece of fruit. Then a 
series of Bar-Ba-Loots jump onto Lou's head and stand on one 
another's shoulders to get to some fruit high in the tree. 
Pipsqueak is passed up the chair of Bar-Ba-Loots and he grabs 
the fruit for the group.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 24.


In the tuft above them, a SWOMEE-SWAN flies off into the sky, 
revealing a nest with BILL, a baby Swomee-Swan, in it. Bill 
YAWNS and HONKS at camera.

We follow the Swomee-Swan as it flies through the forest, 
past a stream and to a clear blue pond where--

The Trio of Humming-Fish climb out of the water onto a rock 
and HUM like an a cappella group. Then they slide back down 
into the water and their HUMMING becomes GURGLING.

Melvin pulls the wagon down into the valley, where all of the 
curious animals gather around them. The Once-ler hops down 
from the wagon with his guitar and starts begins rocking out.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D) 
         This is it!

Two Bar-Ba-Loots look at each other, confused.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D)
         This is the place!
         These Truffula Trees are just'a 
         what I need!

The Bar-Ba-Loots hear him playing and come over to 
investigate.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D)
         Gonna chop one down and make my 
         Thneed.
         But first--

THWACK! As he stands up he accidentally smacks a Bar-ba-loot 
with his guitar.

Then he tosses it up into the air and runs off screen. One 
Bar-Ba-Loot pushes another out of the way as the guitar falls 
back down to the ground and nearly clobbers him.

The Once-ler sings and dances through the valley, followed by 
the curious animals.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D)
         Na na nanana na 
         Na na nanana na
             (to animals) 
         Now you!

The animals, caught up in the music, join in singing and 
dancing with the Once-ler.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 25.


                   ANIMALS
         Na na nanana na
         Nana na nana na na na!

Lou gets into it and doesn't realize the other animals have 
danced off after the Once-ler. He opens his eyes and runs 
after them.

                   ONCE-LER
         That's great!
             (scats to the music)

                   ANIMALS
         Na na nanana na
         Nana na nana na na na!
         Bob-shoo-bop 
         Bob-shoo-bop

He goes into the back of the wagon, pulls out a spatula, and 
sings into it like a microphone.

                   ONCE-LER
         So now our friendship can begin. 
         Hand-and-hand and wing and fin.

The Once-ler goes back into the wagon and begins unpacking, 
obliviously tossing tools over his head at the animals.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D)
         There's nothing you and I can't do 
         So let's all make my dreams come 
         true!
         Yodelhoo...
         Yodelay-hee-hoo...

A saw, shovel, pruning shears, and an axe land right in front 
of different animals, almost hitting them. Then a hair 
trimmer bounces past shaving the stomach of a Bar-Ba-Loot, 
who quickly covers up, embarrassed.

A tube of toothpaste lands in front of a Humming-Fish. Then 
a mallet lands on that, squirting the toothpaste all over his 
face.

A beard trimmer flies out and shaved one of the Bar-Ba-Loots. 
A tube of toothpaste explodes on another one.

                   ANIMALS
         Na na nanana na
         Nana na nana na na na! 
         Na na nanana na
         Nana na nana na na na!

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 26.


The wagon unpacked, the oblivious Once-ler pulls out an axe 
and goes for the big finish.

                   ONCE-LER
         Oh Yodelay-Yodelay-heee-h0000--

Instead of jubilantly joining in the chorus, the angry mob of 
animals have all turned against the Once-ler.

One Swomee-Swan has a stick and taps it against his winged- 
palm menacingly.

                   LOU
         Na na nanana na

Lou dances over and then notices that everyone else is angry 
and he stops singing.

                   ONCE-LER
         Hey, guys. Come on! Where's my 
         back up chorus?

The Bar-Ba-Loots GROWL at the Once-ler.

A Humming-Fish picks up a set of egg beaters and winds them 
menacingly.


EXT: TRUFFULA VALLEY - PAST - CONTINUOUS

The Once-ler turns back to his wagon and grabs TWO LARGE 
SACKS.

                   ONCE-LER
         Ah-ha!

Then he realizes they are filled with marshmallows.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D)
         Oh!

An Angry Bar-ba-loot lunges for him and the Once-ler screams 
like a girl, holding the sack up as a shield. RIIIIP! 
MARSHMALLOWS fly out into the air.

The marshmallow rain down into the angry animals' mouths, who 
eat them. MMMMM! It's like a switch has been flipped.

                   ANIMALS
         O000h!

They all love marshmallows! All of the animals frolic and 
play in them.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 27.


A Bar-Ba-Loot jumps through the air in slo-mo catching one in 
his mouth.

Down below, other Bar-Ba-Loots spin around grabbing as many 
in their mouths as they can. Humming-Fish eat ones floating 
in the water.

A Swomee-Swan drops Pipsqueak down into the pond, which is 
filled with them. A Humming Fish rides on a Bar-Ba-Loot 
through the marshmallows like a Gondolier.

The Once-ler looks down at Pipsqueak who has a huge smile, 
revealing dozens of marshmallows crammed in his mouth. 
Clearly he's going for the record. The Once-ler looks down 
at him with a smile.

                   TED (O.S.)
         Hey-hey-hey-hey. Wait. Wait a 
         minute.

The Once-ler looks around to see where the voice is coming 
from.


EXT: LERKIM - PRESENT - NIGHT

Back to the Once-ler looking down at Ted from his Lerkim.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Excuse me?

                   TED
         Um, yeah, that's awesome. You 
         know, feeding junk food to forest 
         animals. That's great. But, uh, 
         is there a musical number where you 
         show me how to get a tree? 'Cause 
         I'd love to hear that one.

Beat.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Oh, yes. Right after the musical 
         number about the kid who kept 
         interrupting the story and was 
         never heard from again. Mm-hm.

Beat.

                   TED
         Right, got it.
             (gestures with hand) 
         Proceed.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 28.


EXT: TRUFFULA VALLEY - PAST - DAY

The Once-ler puts on a pair of work gloves and grabs a large 
AXE.

                   ONCE-LER
         All right! Here we go. About to 
         make a Thneed. About to change the 
         world.

The animals all stare at the shiny metal axe and watch the 
Once-ler as he walks over to the tall Truffula tree.

He raises the axe up over his head. The animals watch 
curiously.

CHOP! The axe cuts into the tree with a sound that echoes 
through the valley.

The tree creaks and moans as it falls and hits the ground 
with a THUD.

The animals react in horror. What did he just do? 

The Once-ler stares at the tree, impressed.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D) 
         Check it out guys... Huh?

He looks around, noticing all of the animals are gone.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D) 
         Oh, where'd everybody go?

He shrugs, then grabs the tree by the trunk and drags it away 
toward his cottage.


EXT: LERKIM - PRESENT - NIGHT

The Once-ler continues the story.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Little did I know that by chopping 
         down that tree I had just summoned 
         a mystical creature as old as time 
         itself. The legendary--slightly
         annoying--guardian of the forest.
             (beat)
         The Lorax.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 29.


EXT. TRUFFULA VALLEY - PAST - DAY

The animals investigate the stump. A Humming-Fish pokes at 
it.

Suddenly the ground starts rumbling. The animals scatter.

There's a LOUD NOISE and a FLASH OF LIGHT as a thunderstorm 
shoots out of the stump. The animals watch from a safe 
distance.

The one fish slaps the other fish for poking the stump.

The Swomee-Swans shove their head in the ground like 
ostriches. A Bar-Ba-Loot tries it and knocks himself out.

A series of lightning bolts hit the stump causing an 
explosion that reverberates through the valley.

Lou struggles to stand up in the wind. A fish flies into his 
face, knocking him over.

The whole thunderstorm is sucked back into the stump and out 
pops--

THE LORAX. Shortish, brownish, and in charge. He slowly 
stands up. Sees the stump, reacts horrified.

                   LORAX
             (in disbelief)
         What the w-- Who the-- Oh!

The animals watch as he collects some ROCKS and stacks them 
on the stump, creating a memorial. Pipsqueak sees this. He 
brings over a rock and offers it to the Lorax. Other animals 
join him.

When they are done they take a moment of silence for the 
stump. Pipsqueak walks over and holds the Lorax's hand. Lou 
awkwardly grabs the Lorax's other hand and starts blubbering.

Then the Lorax hears the Once-ler WHISTLING and spots him 
ripping tufts from the Truffula tree. The Lorax furrows his 
brow and walks over to investigate.

The Once-ler shakes the tufts like pom-poms as he pulls them 
off the felled tree.

Then he pulls another piece of the tuft and the Lorax comes 
up with it.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         Hey!

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 30.


The Once-ler is startled and trips, falling to the ground.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
             (accusingly)
         Did you chop down this tree?

Pipsqueak curiously wanders over to them.

                   ONCE-LER
         What? Uh... no. Who did it? 
             (gasps, points offscreen) 
         What's that?!

The Lorax looks away and Once-ler drops the axe onto 
Pipsqueak.

                   PIPSQUEAK
         Oy!

                   ONCE-LER
         I think he did it.

The Lorax isn't buying it.

                   LORAX
         Leave! Vacate the premises! Take 
         your axe and get out!

The Once-ler stares at the Lorax.

                   ONCE-LER
         And who are you?

The Once-ler pokes the Lorax in the belly.

                   LORAX
         What-- what?!! I'm-- I'm the 
         Lorax!
             (off Once-ler's blank
              look)
         Guardian of the forest. I speak 
         for the trees.
             (still blank)
         So you're telling me you just 
         didn't see me magically appear out 
         of that stump? With all the 
         lightning and thunder and stuff? 
         You didn't see any of that?

                   ONCE-LER
         No. But that sounds amazing. Can 
         I see some of that?

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 31.


                   LORAX
         Uh... yeah, I could show you. But 
         that's not how it works.

                   ONCE-LER
             (condescending)
         Okay, um... Didn't really happen. 
             (beat)
         Oh, I know what you want!
             (pokes Lorax's nose)

He reaches into his pocket and pulls out a MARSHMALLOW. 
Holds it out.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D) 
             (baby talk)
         I've got one of these for the 
         cutest little guy I ever saw. 
         Yummy-yummy-yummy...

The Lorax stares at the marshmallow.

                   LORAX
         How dare you! Give me that!

He grabs the marshmallow. Sniffs it. It smells good.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         Hmmm... I'm going to eat this, but 
         I am highly offended by it.

He plops it into his mouth. Then makes his way over to the 
Once-ler's tent-house which is being supported by stakes and 
ropes. Kick out a STAKE. The canvas starts to sag.

                   ONCE-LER
         Whoa, what are you-- What?! Hey, 
         mustache! Will you stop that!

The Lorax continues circling around the tent-house pulling up 
stakes. The Once-ler grabs his HAMMER and follows, pounding 
them back in.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D) 
         What's your deal, man?!

                   LORAX
         Time for you to go, beanpole!

They circle faster and faster around the tent-house, the 
Lorax pulling up stakes and the Once-ler pounding them back 
in.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 32.


                   ONCE-LER
         Pull 'em right out and I'm just 
         gonna put 'em right back in. I can 
         do this all day. Unbelievable.

Until the Once-ler turns a corner and is about to bring his 
hammer down on--

Pipsqueak. The Lorax has placed him right where the stake 
would have been. The Lorax holds up his hand to stop the 
Once-ler.

                   LORAX
         Whoa! Stop right there! Stop it! 
         So you'd hammer one of nature's 
         innocent creatures?

The Lorax pats Pipsqueak on the head and he happily runs 
offscreen.

                   ONCE-LER
             (horrified)
         What?! No, I would never hit this 
         little guy. You, on the other 
         hand, I would gladly pound you and 
         your mustache into the ground.

The Lorax turns to all of the watching animals.

                   LORAX
         Behold the intruder and his violent 
         ways!
             (to the Once-ler)
         Shame on you. For shame.

The Once-ler drops the hammer and hides it behind his feet. 
Then he sees all of the animals nodding their heads in 
agreement.

The Once-ler's had it.

                   ONCE-LER
         All right, you know what, that's 
         it.
             (points at Lorax)
         You listen to me, you furry
         meatloaf. I'm gonna chop down as 
         many trees as I need. Okay, news 
         flash, not going anywhere. End of 
         story!

He turns and enters his cottage. His sticks his tongue out 
and does RASPBERRIES to the Lorax before slamming the door 
behind him.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 33.


INT: ONCE-LER'S COTTAGE - PAST - CONTINUOUS 

The Once-ler sighs heavily, shaking his head.

                   LORAX (O.S.)
         Then you leave me no choice.

Startled, the Once-ler turns and sees that the Lorax is 
somehow inside with him. He points a threatening finger at 
the Once-ler and speaks in a spooky voice as if he's casting 
a spell.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         If you're not gone by the time the 
         sun sets on this valley, all the 
         forces of nature will be unleashed 
         upon you and curse you until the 
         end of your days!
             (beat)
         You have been warned.

Lorax turns to make a dramatic exit, but can't reach the 
doorknob of Once-ler's door. He hops a couple of times.

Finally, the Once-ler lets him out.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         Thanks.

                   ONCE-LER 
         Yeah, okay.

Then:

                   LORAX
         You have been warned!

The Lorax storms out and slams the door, leaving the Once-ler 
alone in his cottage.


EXT: LERKIM - PRESENT - NIGHT

Back to the Once-ler looking down at Ted from his Lerkim. 
Ted is clearly entranced by the story.

                   ONCE-LER (0.S.)
         But I didn't listen to his warning. 
         And you won't believe what happened 
         that night...

                   TED
         What?

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 34.


Beat.

                   ONCE-LER (0.S.)
         If you want to hear more, come back 
         tomorrow.

                   TED
         Hey, wait, wait! Tomorrow?

The Whisper-Ma-Phone gets pulled back up. Ted leaps up and 
grabs it, getting carried up.

                   TED (CONT'D)
         Wh0000a!

The Whisper-Ma-Phone retracts into the shutters. Ted is 
flipped up into a bucket hanging near the window.

                   TED (CONT'D)
         Are you serious right now? Ugh! 
         You live in the middle of nowhere! 
         It stinks out here! Don't make me 
         come back.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Then I guess you don't really want 
         to hear the rest of the story.

Once-ler quickly drops the bucket down, and Ted with it. The 
bucket stops right before the ground and the claw comes down 
and knocks Ted out of it. Ted gets back up and shouts up to 
the Once-ler.

                   TED
         No, no, no, no, I do. I really do. 
         I wanna hear the story, I just--

                   ONCE-LER (0.S.)
         Nah! You don't have what it takes. 
         Goodbye!

His green arms leave the window. Ted realizes he's pushed 
too much, and does an about-face.

                   TED
         Wait, wait, wait! I have what it 
         takes. It's alright. It's okay. 
         I'll come back. It's no problem!

Ted turns and quickly heads down the path back to his 
scooter.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 35.


                   TED (CONT'D) 
         See, here I am leaving! Walking 
         away now. I'll see you tomorrow!

The Once-ler watches Ted as he runs down the path.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.) 
             (to himself)
         Hmmmmm. Maybe...just maybe.


INT: AUDREY'S HOUSE - TED'S DAYDREAM - DAY

CLOSE ON a BIRTHDAY CAKE with sixteen candles. Audrey stands 
in front of the cake as a bunch of PARTYGOERS sing.

                   PARTYGOERS 
         Happy Birthday to you!

Audrey closes her eyes, makes a wish, and blows out the 
candles.

                   WOMAN (O.S.) 
         What'd you wish for, Audrey?

Audrey smiles.

                   AUDREY
         Well, I'd love to tell you, but 
         sadly, according to the universal 
         wish laws, I cannot.

                   TED (O.S.) 
         Oh, I know what she wished for.

Audrey turns and sees Ted playing the piano on a balcony 
above. In a TUXEDO. He hops onto the railing of a spiral 
staircase and slides down to the first floor, where he 
continues sliding past a WAITER who holds a tray with an 
milkshake. Ted grabs it as he continues sliding to a TALL 
OBJECT covered with a VELVET CLOTH.

                   TED (CONT'D)
         Was it perhaps...
             (takes a sip from the 
              shake)
         Uh--this?

He removes the velvet cloth, revealing a POTTED TRUFFULA 
TREE. The party erupts in CHEERS and APPLAUSE and FLASHBULBS 
POP. Audrey can't believe her eyes.

                   AUDREY
         Ted, you-- You didn't.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 36.


                   TED
         Oh, no, I totally did. Happy 
         Birthday, Audrey.

                   AUDREY
         Oh...

The crowd starts chanting.

                   PARTYGOERS 
         Kiss him! Kiss him! Kiss him!

Ted turns to Audrey and shrugs. What can we do?

Audrey looks Ted right in the eyes. She moves in for a kiss 
and Ted puckers up.

                   TED'S MOM'S VOICE (O.S.)
         Ted!


INT: DINING ROOM - PRESENT - MORNING

Ted comes out of his daydream. He is sitting at the table 
kissing a CEREAL BOX (EMPTY-O'S).

                   TED'S MOM 
         Ted. Tedster.

                   TED
         Huh?

His Mom sits next to him.

                   TED'S MOM
         You're kissing the cereal again, 
         hon.

Ted realizes he's been caught kissing a cereal box.

                   TED
         What? I just...I like-- I like 
         this cereal. What one is this? 
         Yeah!

Ted shoves a huge spoonful of cereal in his mouth.

                   TED'S MOM
         0-kay... Well I'll make sure to buy 
         extra next time for you.

Ted gets up and rushes for the door.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 37.


                   TED
         All right, cool. Hey, I gotta run. 
         I gotta go do...a thing...so... 
         I'll see you guys.

Mom quickly reaches out a hand and grabs him by his shirt 
collar, stopping him.

                   TED'S MOM
         Whoa, whoa, whoa! You're not going 
         anywhere, young man. It's Sunday. 
         You know what that means? Family 
         time. And we're all playing board 
         games!

Ted's face falls. Grammy Norma watches, interested.

                   TED
         But--


INT: TED'S HOUSE - PRESENT - DAY

Ted sits at the table with his Mom and Grammy Norma playing a 
word game. Grammy Norma surveys the board, holding a letter 
in each hand.

                   GRAMMY NORMA 
         Hmmm. Hmmm. Oooh! No...

Ted SIGHS.

                   TED
             (whispers to himself) 
         Oh man...

Mom is also getting frustrated.

                   TED'S MOM
             (to Grammy Norma)
         Mom, seriously--every turn?

                   GRAMMY NORMA 
         Hey, back off!
             (surveys the board) 
         Oooh! No.

Ted's head hits the table. Mom stands up. She's had it.

                   TED'S MOM
         Okay, Family Time is over! It is 
         now Personal Time, I'll be in my 
         room!

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 38.


                   GRAMMY NORMA 
         Oh, okay, dear. Have fun!

She heads upstairs to her room. As soon as she's gone Ted 
turns to see Grammy's face right next to his.

                   TED
         Whoa!

                   GRAMMY NORMA
         I knew I could break her. Go.

Ted's confused. Grammy Norma gestures to the door.

                   GRAMMY NORMA (CONT'D) 
         Go see him!

Ted realizes what she means. Smiles.

                   TED
         Oh, yeah! You rule! Thank you, 
         Grammy!

And he runs out the door.


EXT: THNEEDVILLE - PRESENT - DAY

Ted rides his scooter through the street on his way back to 
the door out of town.


EXT: ALLEY - PRESENT - CONTINUOUS

Ted turns into an alley and runs into someone. He falls off 
his scooter. He looks up at Mooney and McGurk. Mooney sips 
from a tiny O'Hare Air can and then crushes it with his 
fingers. They step aside revealing, Aloysius O'Hare, who 
uses their hands to walk down to the ground from his car.

                   O'HARE
         Hey, Ted, right?

He signs a document and then sticks his pen in the palm of 
Mooney's hand. Mooney GROANS.

                   TED
             (a bit creeped out) 
         Uh... Mr. O'Hare.

O'Hare gives Mooney and McGurk a look. They close like 
automatic doors, completely sealing off the alleyway. O'Hare 
puts a hand on Ted's shoulder.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 39.


                   O'HARE
         So I hear you've become interested 
         in trees. What's that all about?

                   TED
             (chuckles nervously)
         Oh, um... Where'd you hear that?

O'Hare smiles.

                   O'HARE
         Oh, Teddy, there's not much that 
         goes on in Thneedville that I don't 
         know about.
             (beat)
         Here's the deal. I make a living 
         selling fresh air to people.
         Trees, oh, they make it for free. 
         So when I hear people talking about 
         them, I consider it kind of a 
         threat to my business.
             (growls)

                   TED
         C'mon, I don't even know what
         you're talking about, I...

O'Hare, furious, gets right in Ted's face.

                   O'HARE
         Listen to me, boy. Don't go poking
         around in things you don't 
         understand. Or I'll be your worst 
         nightmare! I'm Frankenstein's head 
         on a spider's body!

Ted nods, trying not to freak out.

                   TED
         Yeah, um, okay... my mom's 
         expecting me so I'm just gonna--

                   O'HARE
             (chuckles)
         Of course, of course, now go back 
         to your family game time. Grandma 
         just finished her turn.

                   TED
         How-- How did you know?

                   O'HARE
         Please. I have eyes everywhere.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 40.


Mounted security cameras turn to face Ted. The eyes of a 
BABY IN A BILLBOARD move to look at him. A ROBOT CAT turns 
its head 180 degrees to stare at him.

                   O'HARE (CONT'D)
         You got a beautiful town here, Ted. 
         Lots of fun stuff to occupy your 
         short attention span. Why I can't 
         think of any reason you'd ever want 
         to go outside of town again. Ever.

O'Hare gestures to Mooney and McGurk, who menacingly 
straighten the kinked neck of Ted's scooter and slap Ted's 
helmet on his head. They open up the alley exit. Ted 
quickly scooters away.

                   O'HARE (CONT'D)
             (calls after him)
         Okay! Good talk! Really good 
         talk.

The three of them get into O'Hare's car.

Ted waits around the corner for the car to leave. He gets a 
determined look on his face, turns around, and scooters 
toward the end of town.


EXT: LERKIM - PRESENT - DAY

Ted arrives out of breath. Runs up to the door and RINGS the 
doorbell. This starts to set off the giant hammer again. 
Ted's face falls. He forgot.

                   TED
         Oh no.

He quickly jumps out of the way and tumbles to the ground as 
the Seussian machine does its stuff.

                   TED (CONT'D)
         Look out!

Then calls up to the window.

                   TED (CONT'D)
         Hey, man! Hey! You know, you need 
         to change that doorbell!

The Once-ler's eyes appear in the boarded-up window.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Awww, you missed me.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 41.


                   TED
         What?

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         You're already back. Clearly you 
         missed me... a little, right?

                   TED
         No I didn't. I just-- I'm here to 
         hear the end of the story.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Why are you so interested in trees, 
         anyway? Why aren't you like other 
         kids, break-dancing and wearing 
         bell-bottoms and playing the Donkey 
         Kongs?

Ted reacts--"break-dancing"? "Donkey Kong"?

                   TED
             (playing it off)
         Yeah, right, right... Yeah, I don't 
         know, I just-- I just, you know, 
         thought it would be kinda cool to 
         have one, you know.

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.) 
         Ahhh...It's a girl, isn't it?

                   TED
         Pffft!
             (laughs) 
         What? No!

                   ONCE-LER (O.S.)
         Really? 'Cause when a guy does 
         something stupid once, well, that's 
         because he's a guy. But if he does 
         the same stupid thing twice, it's 
         usually to impress some girl.

                   TED
         Hey, she is not "some girl." She's 
         a woman. In high school. And she 
         loves trees and I'm going to get 
         her one.

The Once-ler's yellow eyes stare down from the window, almost 
seeming to smile.

                   ONCE-LER (0.S.)
         Aww, how nice to see someone so 
         undeterred by things like REALITY.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 42.


                   TED
             (earnestly) 
         Thank you.

                   ONCE-LER (0.S.)
         All right, where did we leave off?


EXT: ONCE-LER'S COTTAGE - PAST - NIGHT

A Humming-Fish jumps out of the pond and catches a FIREFLY in 
his mouth. When he comes back up from the water his eyes 
glow, scaring his two Humming-Fish friends.


INT: ONCE-LER'S COTTAGE - PAST - NIGHT

The Once-ler finishes knitting his THNEED. He holds it up, 
admiring it with a smile.

                   ONCE-LER
         Now that's a Thneed! Nothing 
         unmanly about knitting. No sir.

He sets it on a chair. Stifles a yawn. Then crawls into 
bed, turns out the light, and closes his eyes. He begins 
SNORING, sound asleep.


INT: ONCE-LER'S COTTAGE - PAST - NIGHT

CREEEEAK! The sleeping Once-ler doesn't wake at the sound of 
the door slowly opening. Then the faint sound of tiny 
footsteps can be heard shuffling across the floor.

The Once-ler's bed raises up off the ground several inches 
and begins to move toward the door.

Lou backs into the stove and burns himself.

It's almost to the door when we hear a THUD!

Several animals struggle to carry the Once-ler's bed.

They reach the front door of the house -- the bed won't fit. 
BANG BANG BANG!

                   LORAX
         Look at that-- That-- You-- Oh!

                   ONCE-LER 
             (in his sleep) 
         What?

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 43.


The animals drop the bed.

                   LORAX
             (slaps his forehead)
         Who taught you guys how to steal a 
         bed?


EXT: ONCE-LER'S HOUSE - PAST - LATER

The Lorax directs the animals from outside as they finally 
manage to get the bed out through the window.

Melvin sees this and WHINNIES. The Lorax approaches him with 
some Truffula fruit. Melvin takes it as payment to keep 
quiet.


EXT: TRUFFULA VALLEY - PAST - NIGHT

Under the pale moonlight, we see THREE HUMMING-FISH humming 
the MISSION IMPOSSIBLE THEME. Then the silhouettes of the 
Lorax and several other animals tiptoe as they carry the Once- 
ler's bed from his home, down the hill toward a flowing
river. Lou runs after them, huffing and puffing, trying to 
keep up.


EXT: RIVERBANK - PAST - CONTINUOUS

The Lorax and the animals come to a halt at the edge of the 
river. The Lorax smiles as he addresses his accomplices.

                   LORAX
             (whispering)
         Okay, nice and easy.

The Lorax and the animals quietly slip the bed into the river 
and watch as it calmly floats downstream. The Lorax turns to 
the animals, beaming.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         Nice work, you guys. Couldn't've 
         done it without you.

He turns and waves to the Once-ler as he floats away. The 
Lorax's face falls as he sees Pipsqueak waving back at him, 
sitting on top of the sleeping Once-ler and floating 
downstream.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         You gotta to be kidding me. Can he 
         swim?
                   (MORE)

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 44.

                   LORAX (CONT'D) 
             (Pipsqueak's Mom shakes 
              her head no)
         Of course he can't swim! 
             (to Pipsqueak)
         Hang on, Pipsqueak! I'm coming to
         getcha!

The Lorax and animals take off running along side the 
floating bed. Lou rolls his eyes and runs after them.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         Hey, you fishies! Stop that bed!

They swim up to the bed and try to pull it over to the side, 
but the blanket and top sheet rips off, covering them.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         Oh!

Still sleeping, the Once-ler shivers and grabs Pipsqueak and 
uses him like a blanket.

The Lorax points to a LOW-HANGING BRANCH. He directs the 
animals up the tree.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         Jump! Jump! C'mon get up there! 
         C'mon! Go go! Little bit more! 
         Little bit more!

The branch doesn't hang low enough.

                   LORAX (CONT'D) 
         Ugh! Now what?

Lorax looks over to see Lou standing next to him stuffing his 
face with fruit.

The Lorax struggles to push Lou up the tree.

                   LORAX (CONT'D) 
         C'mon! Get up there! Whoa!

The branch hangs low enough to reach Pipsqueak. Pipsqueak 
sees the Lorax and Bar-Ba-Loots hanging from the branch 
trying to save him. The Lorax stretches out his hand...

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         Okay, Pipsqueak, give me your hand. 
         C'mon, reach out for the Lorax.

...but Pipsqueak grabs FRUIT hanging from the tree instead 
and takes a big bite.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 45.


                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         Where'd you go?
             (slaps his forehead)
         What are you?! Bar-Ba-Loots...

The Once-ler's foot now drops into the water. Like a rudder, 
it re-directs the bed to a side stream. The Lorax's face 
falls.

                   LORAX (CONT'D) 
         Oh, that's bad.

The bed passes by the Three Humming-Fish standing on a lily 
pad who are HUMMING "TAPS".

Suddenly, Pipsqueak whimpers and a look of terror comes over 
his face as he looks downstream and sees rapids approaching.

                   LORAX (CONT'D) 
         Hey, Beanpole! Wake up!

Pipsqueak runs to the end of the bed, which flips upside down 
in the water. Then it flips right side up again. The Once- 
ler is covered in fish who quickly jump back off the bed and 
into the water.

The Once-ler wakes up, spitting water out of his mouth. He 
looks at Pipsqueak holding onto the bed frame and waving to 
him. Pipsqueak CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY.

                   ONCE-LER
         Uh, what's happening? Where is-- 
         Where am I?

Then he sees the Lorax running alongside him on the shore. 
His face falls.

The Lorax points to the rapids ahead.

                   LORAX
         Hey, you got trouble and it's 
         coming up fast!

The Once-ler turns and sees the approaching rapids.

                   ONCE-LER
         Aaah! We're in a river!

The river is picking up speed. Pipsqueak and the Once-ler 
hold on for dear life as the bed hits the whitewater and bobs 
up and down.

                   ONCE-LER AND PIPSQUEAK 
         Whhhhhh0000000aaaaa!

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 46.


Finally the whitewater ends. The Once-ler and Pipsqueak 
breathe sighs of relief. They LAUGH at the fact that they 
survived and then see the waterfall ahead of them.

                   PIPSQUEAK 
         Ewww... 

                   ONCE-LER
         Oh no.

He and Pipsqueak SCREAM in fear. The Once-ler unsuccessfully 
tries to use his pillow to paddle away from the waterfall.
He calls to the Lorax.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D) 
         Just do something!

The Lorax looks around. Spots a GIANT BOULDER up high above 
the waterfall.

                   LORAX
         Help is on the way!

The bed heads closer and closer to the falls.

                   ONCE-LER
             (mutters to himself) 
         What the-- Oh no!

The Lorax quickly scampers up to the boulder with a STICK. 
Wedges the stick under the boulder. Tries to dislodge it.

                   LORAX
         Just a minute!

He jumps up and down on the stick. The boulder gets 
dislodged and rolls down the hill.

At the end of the hill is a small slope going up, which send 
the boulder flying.

The Once-ler and Pipsqueak, about to go over the waterfall, 
now see a giant boulder flying at them.

                   ONCE-LER AND PIPSQUEAK 
         Aaaaaaaaahhhhhhhhhhhhh!!!

THUMP! The boulder connects with the far side of the bed, 
catapulting the Once-ler and Pipsqueak off of it.

The bed crashes over the falls. Violently.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 47.


THUD! The Once-ler bounces and slides along the ground on 
his back, holding Pipsqueak up in the air, so he wouldn't get 
hurt.

                   PIPSQUEAK
         Huh.

Pipsqueak looks over to the Lorax who appears on the scene, 
seeing the Once-ler lying unconscious. His eyes go wide.

                   LORAX
         O000! Oh no...
             (slaps the Once-ler) 
         Wake up! Wake up!

The Lorax knows what he needs to do, but doesn't want to do 
it.

The animals watch as the Lorax pinches the Once-ler's nose 
and tips his head back. He takes a deep breath and lowers 
his lips to the Once-ler's.

The Lorax comes up and wipes off his tongue. That didn't 
work, so he grabs two Bar-Ba-Loots, rubbing them together to 
create a static charge that he uses to shock the Once-ler.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         Clear!

The Lorax jumps back as the Once-ler wakes up. He 
immediately reaches out and hugs the Lorax.

                   ONCE-LER
         Haha! I was heading into the light 
         and you pulled me right back and 
         here I am! You saved my life!

The Lorax squirms guiltily as the Once-ler hugs him.

                   LORAX
         Yeah, no...I know. Well, no, it's 
         not that big a deal.

                   ONCE-LER
         It is a big deal! Look, I almost 
         went over that waterfall--
             (breaks off hug,
              realizing)
         In my bed... How did my bed get in 
         the river?

The Lorax avoids eye contact with the Once-ler.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 48.


                   LORAX
         Oh, about that, actually... 
         um...I...
             (under his breath)
         Putyourbedinthewater.

The Once-ler drops the Lorax.

                   LORAX (CONT'D)
         I didn't mean you any harm! I just 
         wanted to calmly float you away. 
             (beat)
         Look, everyone here needs the
         trees. And you're chopping 'em 
         down. So we've got a big problem.

The Once-ler looks down and sees Pipsqueak holding on to his 
leg, looking up at him with puppy-dog eyes. Pipsqueak nods. 
The Once-ler looks at all the animals. The Lorax. Finally, 
it begins to sink in. He kneels down and address the
animals.

                   ONCE-LER
             (holds up his hand to
              swear)
         Alright, look, I hereby swear that 
         I will never chop down another 
         tree. I promise!

The Lorax looks him over.

                   LORAX
         Thank you. But I'm gonna keep my 
         eye on you.

                   ONCE-LER
         Good. Now, I've got a big day 
         tomorrow, so I'm going to get some 
         sleep.

The Once-ler heads off toward his house. The animals all 
CHEER. The Once-ler stops and walks back toward the falls.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D) 
         Right after I find my bed.

The other Baby Bar-Ba-Loot touches a fish next to him, 
shocking it.

Dr. Seuss' The Lorax  1-6-12 Final Locked Reels Conform 49.


EXT: TRUFFULA VALLEY - PAST - MORNING

FADE IN on another beautiful morning in Truffula Valley. 
Reveal the Humming-fish Trio CROWING like roosters on top of 
one of the trees.


INT: ONCE-LER'S COTTAGE - PAST - SAME

The Once-ler wakes up from a good night's sleep. Then turns 
and finds--

The Lorax. Lying next to him in the bed, SNORING. He 
SCREAMS.

                   ONCE-LER
         Aaaaiiiigggghhhhh!

This wakes up the Lorax.

                   LORAX
         Aaaiiiiggghhhhh!

                   ONCE-LER AND LORAX 
         Aaaiiiiggghhhhhh!!!

Lorax punches the Once-ler.

                   ONCE-LER
         Ow. Okay, uh... What are you, I-I--

The Once-ler looks around. He turns to the Lorax.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D)
         Question... what are they doing 
         here?

We reveal his place is filled with animals. Bar-ba-loots 
curled up at the foot of his bed, Swomee-Swans nesting in 
light fixtures, and Humming-fish in drawers. A sleeping Bar- 
Ba-Loot SNEEZES, knocking the Baby Bar-Ba-Loot on it's 
stomache onto the ground.

                   ONCE-LER (CONT'D)
             (beat)
         And follow up, if I may, what are 
         YOU doing here?!

                   LORAX
         Well, after "the incident" last 
         night we found one of your socks 
         and came here to return it. But 
         when we got here, you were asleep.

